

ROMA CHEEMA

EMPLOYEE RELATION SPECIALIST

PERSONAL PROFILE

Avid professional with experience in a fast-paced Human Resources department. Incomparable ability to prioritize and execute multiple HR projects and deadlines concurrently. Unmatchable organizational, time management, and interpersonal skills. Procedure in administering corporate HR initiatives, providing a broad level of counseling on recruitment, employee relations, retention and training programs, and handling complex situations with professionalism and confidentiality. Expert knowledge of local, state, district, and country laws influencing personnel actions.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- Organized Kids Entrepreneurship Boot-camp (Oh My Genius).
- DayCare.
- Organized Talent Show (Bima got talent), Organized Sports Day, Various events won the trophy in Cricket match held at Bima.
- Won the trophy in cricket match held at Bima Milvik Mobile Pakistan.
- Won the first prize twice in Bima Got Talent .
- Made Monthly event calendar.

CERTIFICATES

Diploma in Marketing
Diploma in Human Resource
management Bima
Got Talent (09/2017 – 01/2018)
Certificate of Value Award Kids
Entrepreneurship Boot-Camp
(Oh my Genius)

EDUCATION HISTORY

STUDY PROGRAM

Lahore College Graduation 04/2004

Courses (Kinnaird College for Women)

Diploma in marketing

Diploma in Human Resource Management

MBA Executive Continue form Superior University

WORK EXPERIENCE

Bahria Town (Mall of Lahore)

HR Generalist (HR Department)

01-2021-Present

- Finalization of the payroll on Oracle soft ware.
- Recruitment and Selection.
- · Compensation and Benefit.
- Handling queries of employees and providing assistance to them.
- Grievance Handling.
- Managing advance Salary, Loans, Help Cases.
- Preparation of Offer and Appointment letters.
- Preparation of New Contracts of Employees.
- New Joiner's Orientation.
- · Managing the database of resumes.
- · Scheduling interviews.
- Coordinating with line managers in order to finalize the Job descriptions of their staff.
- Managing the Pre-Employment Medical screening process (forms & reports).
- Maintaining employee files and ensuring that employee documentation is complete.
- · Bank account opening of staff.
- Training of New hiring Staff.
- Handling of employee warnings & terminations.
- Ensuing timely processing of final clearance / settlements of outgoing employees.
- Processing Overtime claims & Description
 amp; other reimbursements.
- Filing of All Employees (Joiners & Leavers).
- Leave Management.
- Attendance Management system.
- Day to Day HR Operations.
- Any other Duties assigned by HOD.



ORGANIZATION

BPO11 (TECHNOLOGY OUTSOURCE COMPANY)

2008-2015 PR EXECUTIVE

MILVIK MOBILE PAKISTAN (BIMA) 06/2015 - 02/2020

EMPLOYEE RELATION SPECIALIST HR OFFICER

SUPERIOR UNIVERSITY (CMACED) 06/2015 - 09/2020

OPERATION EXECUTIVE

EDWAGS FURNITURE INDUSTRY 10/2020 - PRESENT

SENIOR EXECUTIVE CULTURE AND ENGAGEMENT

SKILLS

MS Office (Word, Excel, Power Point) Internet Email Interactive White Boards Educational Mobile Apps ELearning Websites (Planetsherston.com & 3P Learning)

LANGUAGES

Urdu, English, Punjabi FULL PROFICIENCY

INTERESTS

EDWAGS

FURNITURE INDUSTRY
 Senior Executive Culture and Engagement
 (HR Department)

10/2020 - 12-2020

Achievement and Tasks

- Develop and implement strategies to increase Diversity & Inclusion within the organization.
- Manage Performance Appraisal process and assist with goal development. Collaborate on suggestions for individual training that will enhance growth and development.
- Participate in coaching, counseling and advising management and staff to ensure resolution of employment related matters.
- Prepare and analyze HR metrics and provide reports that support decision making in specified areas.
- Create and / or update policies, procedures, and guidelines as needed.
- Implement new, and enhance existing staff recognition and reward programs.
- Participate in the exit interview process.
- · Any other duties assigned by C.E.O

OPERATIONS EXECUTIVE

Superior University

02/2020 - 09/2020

Achievement and Tasks

- Updating the database of all departments. Communication and coordination with internal and external stakeholders.
- · Planning and execution of operational activities.
- Writing reports & containing the progress of all departments.
- Close coordination with social media team to ensure social media presence.
- Operational support to all departments.
- Guest protocols & documentation and taking meeting of Minutes.
- Supporting departments on the team events.
- Monitoring branding and designing of each activity before the upload and get the approval from GM.



EMPLOYEE RELATION SPECIALIST

Human Resource Department Bima Mobile Pakistan

• 06/2015 - 02/2020

Insurance company

Achievements/Tasks

- Preparing or updating employment records related to hiring, transferring, promoting, and terminating.
- Explaining human resources policies, procedures, laws, and standards to
- · Ensuring new hire paperwork is completed and processed.
- Informing job applicants of job duties, responsibilities, benefits schedules, working conditions, promotions opportunities, etc.
- Addressing any employment relations issues, such as work complaints and harassment allegations.
- Processing all personnel actions forms and ensuring proper approval
- Overseeing hiring process, which includes coordinating job posts, reviewing resumes, and performing reference checks.
- Organized HCD (Human Central Design) session.
- Gather and evaluate information from employees and management on previous training to identify weaknesses and areas that need additional training.
- Attend seminars and meetings to learn new training methods and techniques and use the knowledge to prepare and coordinate future training sessions.
- Recruit and train new Trainers, delegate training tasks to the new Trainers and evaluate performance.
- Includes the Marketing of company training opportunities to employees and provide information on benefits to encourage participation.
- Inform employees on scheduled training and track their progress.
- Recommend training materials and methods, order and maintain inhouse training equipment and facilities and manage the budget set for training.